dcmp.org 2019-11-07

# Disclaimer / Privacy Policy

## Disclaimer

The contents of the Described and Captioned Media Program website were developed under a grant from the U.S. Department of Education (H327N110002). However, these contents do not necessarily represent the policy of the U.S. Department of Education and you should not assume endorsement by the Federal government. Project Officer, Glinda Hill. 

## Privacy Policy

The National Association of the Deaf, through a grant with the U.S. Department of Education, operates the Described and Captioned Media Program ("DCMP"). The practices of DCMP, with respect to data collected and used by DCMP in connection with this Web site (the "Site"), are governed by this online privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") as amended from time to time, and not the privacy policy in effect at the time the data was collected. Please regularly review our Privacy Policy. If you have objections to the Privacy Policy, you should immediately discontinue use of the Site and follow the procedure described in the section entitled "Updating your personal information and privacy preferences".

The Site is intended for adult audiences, and DCMP does not knowingly collect any personal information from anyone under 13 years of age.

### Changes in Privacy Policy

All personal information ("personal information" is defined as any information that identifies or can be used to identify the person to whom such information pertains) that we collect and maintain will be subject to this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time. DCMP may change the Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion and will provide notice of changes in the Privacy Policy. If as the result of such changes you want to alter the ways in which DCMP is allowed to use your personal information, you can do so by following the procedure described in the section entitled "Updating your personal information and privacy preferences." You will be deemed to have been made aware of, and will be subject to, the changes to the Privacy Policy after such notice has been posted with the following exception: if at the time you provide personal information to DCMP you limit how such information will be used to communicate with you, DCMP will not change your preference in this regard without your express consent.

### Entities collecting personal information

Personal information on this Site is collected on behalf of DCMP by the National Association of the Deaf, who is responsible for this site. The National Association of the Deaf's address is 8630 Fenton Street, Ste 820, Silver Spring, MD 20910 USA, and its telephone number is 301-587-1788. The administrative offices for DCMP are located at 1447 E Main Street, Spartanburg, SC 29307 USA, and can be reached via phone at 864-585-1778.

If the Site contains links to other sites at which personal information is collected, unless expressly provided to the contrary, the collection and use of your personal information will be governed by the privacy policy applicable to that site. That privacy policy should identify the entity that is collecting your personal information.

### Updating your personal information and privacy preferences

You have the right to access and correct your personal information and privacy preferences at any time. With respect to Registration Information (as defined in the section entitled "Protection of your personal information"), this may be accomplished by linking to your account where you can view and make changes to your personal information. You may also correct your personal information and privacy preferences (such as whether you wish to receive promotional communications) by writing DCMP at:

**Described and Captioned Media Program**  
Attn: Change of Address/Privacy   
1447 E Main   
Spartanburg, SC 29307   
USA   
e-mail: [clientservices@dcmp.org](mailto:clientservices@dcmp.org)

Please include your name, address, and/or e-mail address when you contact us.

### Collection of personal information

As a visitor to this Site, you can engage in many activities without providing any personal information. In connection with other activities, DCMP may ask you to provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting a form. It is optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, DCMP may ask that you provide personal information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including ZIP code), e-mail address, telephone and facsimile numbers, and other personal information. Depending upon the activity, some of the information that we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity. Similarly, if you wish to delete your information (pursuant to the mechanism set forth in "Updating your personal information and privacy preferences") that is mandatory, you will no longer be able to engage in a particular activity.

When you use the Site, DCMP may also collect certain information about your computer to facilitate and evaluate your use of the Site. For example, we may log environmental variables, such as browser type, operating system, CPU speed, referring or exit web pages, and the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer. DCMP also uses such information to measure traffic patterns on the Site. We do not match such information with any other information held by DCMP unless we have your consent.

In order to reduce errors in our database, authenticate our users, prevent abuse of our Site, and provide more consistent, relevant experiences to our users, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submit to us with information from third-party sources. For example, if permitted under applicable law, we may supplement your Registration Information with address information provided by the U.S. Postal Service to qualify your information and prevent errors in our database. As permissible, we may also supplement the information you provide to us with demographic and other information (such as age or interest in photography) stored in third-party databases in order to make it more likely that marketing communications we send will be of interest to you.

### How your personal information is used

DCMP collects your information in order to record, support and facilitate your participation in the activities you select. Your personal information is also used to track customer preferences and keep you informed about upgrades, special offers, and other services of DCMP and selected third parties unless you have opted not to receive such communications or such communications are prohibited by law.

DCMP may collect information about the use of the Site, such as the number of downloads, types of Services used, how many users we receive daily, and the IP/Internet address of your computer. This information is collected in aggregate form, without identifying any user individually.

DCMP may use this aggregate, nonidentifying statistical data for improving the Site, providing more relevant experiences to our customers and for statistical analysis.

### Your choices with respect to personal information

DCMP recognizes and appreciates the importance of the responsible use of information collected on the Site. DCMP will respect your legal rights regarding access to and correction and deletion of your personal information. DCMP may communicate information to you regarding products, services, and special offers available from DCMP unless you have opted not to receive such communications or such communications are prohibited by law, although we may find it necessary to continue to communicate with you regarding your use of the Site. Except in the particular circumstances described in this Privacy Policy, DCMP will not provide your name to other companies or organizations without your consent.

There are other instances in which DCMP may divulge your personal information, such as where required by law, regulation, or litigation. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that such disclosure should be made for reasons of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance.

### Protection of your personal information

The personal information that you provide in connection with registering yourself as a user of the Site is classified as Registration Information. Registration Information is protected in several ways. Access by you to your Registration Information is available through a password and unique customer ID selected by you. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. In addition, your Registration Information resides on secure servers that only selected DCMP personnel have access to via password. DCMP encrypts your personal information and thereby strives to prevent unauthorized parties from viewing such information when it is transmitted to DCMP.

Personal information that you provide that does not constitute Registration Information also resides on secure servers and is accessible only to selected DCMP personnel via password. Since this information is not accessible online by you, you will not be asked to select a password in order to view or modify such information.

Please note that any information you post to a public bulletin board, chat room, and/or blog is available to all persons accessing that location, and your e-mail address may also be posted on these venues. The information you share, including your e-mail address, would then be available to all persons accessing these venues, and such information may be read, collected or used by others for any purpose, including sending you unsolicited messages. DCMP is not responsible for any information you elect to submit in these venues or the use of such information.

### Tracking, use of cookies, web beacons and similar devices

In order to improve the Site and provide more convenient, relevant experiences to our customers, we may use "cookies", "web beacons", and similar devices to track your activities. A cookie is small amount of data that is transferred to your browser by a web server and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. It functions as your identification card and enables DCMP to record your passwords, purchases, and preferences. It cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses. A web beacon is a small transparent gif image that is embedded in an HTML page or e-mail used to track when the page or e-mail has been viewed.

While DCMP uses cookies and similar devices to track your use of the Site, such as the number of downloads, types of products used, how many users we receive daily, and our web servers automatically log the IP/Internet address of your computer, DCMP does not generally use this information to identify you personally. However, if you expressly provide consent for the Site to "remember" the unique identifier that you select when you register for various activities on the Site, that unique identifier will be stored on a cookie on your computer and that unique identifier will be linked to your Registration Information. As a result, your navigation path around the Site will be tracked.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. (For some web pages that require an authorization, cookies are not optional. Users choosing not to accept cookies or similar devices will probably not be able to access those pages.)

### Privacy complaints

DCMP takes its users' privacy concerns seriously. If you believe that DCMP has not complied with this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information, you may write to the DCMP Privacy Officer at the following address:

**Described and Captioned Media Program**   
Attn: Privacy Officer   
1447 E Main   
Spartanburg, SC 29307   
USA 

e-mail: [privacy-officer@dcmp.org](mailto:privacy-officer@dcmp.org)

If you provide DCMP with inconsistent privacy preferences (for example, by indicating on one occasion that third parties may contact you with marketing offers and indicating on another occasion that they may not), DCMP will endeavor to update your privacy preferences in a timely and accurate manner.

Also, please note that DCMP is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of non-DCMP websites to which this Site or any other DCMP Web site may link. You should review the privacy policy of such sites before using the sites.
